Ritwik Bhriguvanshi

7700 Gleason Drive | Knoxville, TN 37919 | (813) 389-1435 | rbhriguv@vols.utk.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Multilingual, multicultural, futuristic MSBA candidate with emphasis on statistical modeling, data science, financial analysis, business development, and client relations. Former NCAA student athlete with experience of developing and leading diverse teams in competitive environments. Extensive coursework in and use of data visualization/analysis techniques and statistical languages with complementing relationship and communications skills.

EDUCATION

University of Tennessee, Haslam College of Business

Master of Science in Business Analytics

Erskine College

Due West, South Carolina

Bachelor of Science in Accounting, Minor: Mathematics & IT

May 2019

EXPERIENCE

DELL TECHNOLOGIES, Global Services Support Analytics Intern, Remote, US

June 2020 - July 2020

- Investigated gap analyses for 68 commodity classifications to develop mitigation processes with objective of reducing customer response times by 5%
- Developed 11 real time dashboards in Power BI to monitor issue specific KPI's for project managers enabling teams to perform SWOT analyses and integrate training programs for frontline agents
- Formulated global version playbook for four regions (US, Europe, Asia, and Pacific) based on customer experience and telecom metrics to reduce cost and enhance client satisfaction

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT AND INDUSTRY PROJECTS, Knoxville, TN

August 2019 – July 2020

- Researched machine learning algorithms examining Isolation Forest, Novelty Detection, Bayesian Networks, and K-Means Clustering on 10 years of IRS 990 filings to develop anomaly detection Python program for Capital One
- Analyzed Kroger data consisting of over 5 million transactions utilizing Market Basket Analysis, Naïve Bayes
 Method, Random Forest Classification, and Tableau Visualizations to develop analytical insights
- Incorporated real-world supply chain and investment portfolio simulations in ExtendSim and SimQuick for undergraduate students to optimize inventory, reduce lead times, and maximize returns

WOODCHIPS RESTAURANT, Accounting Consultant, Honea Path, SC

February 2019 – April 2019

- Redesigned employee regulation timecard, production & expenditure worksheet, and profit & loss statements with Microsoft Excel and Visual Basic to increase record accuracy/transparency and reduce cash theft
- Forecasted trend analysis to improve revenue & inventory management and optimize warehouse storage, enabling to reduce monthly expenditures by 5%

MODULUS MOTORS, Data Analyst Intern, Manipal, India

May 2018 – August 2018

• Interpreted and analyzed surveyed data with statistical models to identify key metrics to improve decision making; specific focus on data requirements to design marketing plans for expansion and diversification

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Computer: Microsoft Office, R, Python, JMP, SAS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Tableau, Power BI, DAX, ExtendSim, Apache Spark, AWS, MongoDB, Git, Visual Basic, HTML, CSS, RShiny, AMPL, CPLEX, Gurobi

Certifications: Microsoft Office Specialist Excel 2016, Business Statistics and Analysis Specialization (Rice University), IBM Data Science Professional, IMA Data Analytics & Visualization Fundamentals

Language: English, Hindi, Punjabi, Sanskrit (Intermediate)

ACTIVITIES AND HONORS

Student Ambassador for MSBA program, University of Tennessee

Academic Mentor at Thornton Athletic Center

NCAA Division II Student-Athlete & Athletic Scholarship

Student Instructor at Erskine College Mathematics Department

Erskine College Garnet Circle (Top 25 Academic Students)

May 2020 - Present

January 2020 - March 2020

August 2015 - May 2019

August 2017 - May 2019